Guide to the Bernard Gotfryd Photograph Collection PR 276
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Slides
  - Subseries I.3 - Subjects - New York City
    - Demonstrations - Labor, 1969, 1983, 1987 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 49)
    - Demonstrations - Political, 1968-1983, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 50)
    - Demonstrations - Political - War, 1968-1982 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 51)
    - Education - various, 1979-1985, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 52)
    - Events - various, 1970-1981 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 53)
    - Fires - various, 1987, undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 54)
    - Funerals - various, 1969, 1983 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 55)
    - Holidays - various, 1969, 1976, 1987 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 56)
    - Neighborhoods - Civic Center East Harlem (El Barrio) East Village Lower East Side Meatpacking District (Chelsea) Queens - Forest Hills Roosevelt Island Times Square Washington Heights, 1976-1984 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 57)
    - Occupations - various, 1986-1987, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 58)
    - Parks - Central Park Union Square, 1968, 1979, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 59)
    - People - Children Crowds Jewish Americans, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 60)
    - Performing Arts - various, 1969, 1978-1985 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 61)
    - Political Events - various, 1968, 1980 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 62)
    - Poverty - various, circa 1980s (Offsite-box 5, Folder 63)
    - Religious Events - various, 1979, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 64)
    - Restaurants and Food - George's Lunch Maxim's Ottomanelli Brothers River Café Russian Tea Room Zabar's, 1980-1983, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 65)
    - River and Harbor Views - various, 1984-1986, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 66)
    - Statue of Liberty - various, 1976, 1986, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 67)
    - Street Scenes - 42nd Street 76th Street 95th Street Third Avenue Fifth Avenue Madison Avenue Park Avenue Riverside Drive, 1968-1981, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 68)
    - Transportation - various, 1979-1984, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 69)
    - Winter Scenes - various, 1977-1978, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 70)
    - Various and Unidentified, 1985, undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 71)
- Series II. Photographs, 1960's - 1985
  Mounted and unmounted photographs are separated then arranged alphabetically by subject. In many cases, sitters with more than three portraits were issued their own folder. Numbers in parenthesis denote number of images. Photographs larger than 14 x 18 inches have been removed, housed in flat files, and listed separately.
  Subseries II.1 Portraits – Unmounted contains photographs ranging in size from 8 x 10 inches to 11 x 14 inches. Portraits feature actors, artists, athletes, musicians, politicians and writers and include both formal and candid shots. The photographs are arranged alphabetically by name with cross-references when more than one person appears in a single image. A separate folder contains images of musical groups, including The Beatles during an appearance on the Ed Sullivan Show.
  Subseries II.2 Portraits – Unmounted – By Other Photographers includes eight portraits taken by Bernard Gotfryd's first cousin, Alex Gotfryd. Also included are two portraits of Bernard Gotfryd, one by his son, Howard Gotfryd, and the other by Richard Reinhold.
  Subseries II.3 Portraits – Mounted contains portraits that are either matted or mounted to board. As with the unmounted portraits, images include both formal and candid portraits of actors, artists, dancers, politicians and writers.
  Subseries II.4 Subjects – Unmounted consists of photographs of places and events, mainly in New York City. Images are arranged alphabetically by topic. Images of art include several photographs of kinetic and light art, taken at the Howard Wise Gallery in 1967. "Buildings - Printing & Publishing" is comprised of photographs taken during the final day of work at the New York Daily Mirror. This series includes images of the presses, the building and many of the workers. Celebrations include two images of a ticker tape parade for astronauts John Young and Virgil Grissom. Also included is a color photograph of fireworks during the Brooklyn Bridge Centennial celebration. "Children" contains several images of children playing on the streets of New York. One image shows a group of small boys with a shoeshine box. Another shows three boys playing cards outside Pennsylvania Station. "Demonstrations & Parades" contains a single image of Legal Aid employees on strike. "Immigration" is a group of images taken at the Calexico-Mexicali border station. The images are undated, but appear to be from the 1960s. Photographs of newspaper vendors, stockbrokers, street artists and vendors are included in "Occupations." A separate folder contains photographs of police officers. New York City street scenes show daily life in the city, including several images of the city at night. Photographs include a father and daughter eating hot dogs from a vendor. Another image shows a crowded Times Square sidewalk, complete with an advertisement for Metropole Café's "Topless Go Go." John F. Kennedy International Airport's Terminal 5 is represented in "Transportation," along with horse-drawn carriages and a solitary woman riding a bus. Subway images include panhandlers, graffiti and stations, as well as a nun sitting in an unidentified station, reading in front of a Levy's bread advertisement. Photographs of the construction of several unidentified housing projects are located in "Miscellaneous & Unidentified."
  Subseries II.5 Subjects – Mounted is comprised of photographs mounted on board. Two of these images were taken at Robert F. Kennedy's funeral in New York's St. Patrick's Cathedral and burial in Arlington National Cemetery.
  In some cases photographic prints have attached typewritten notes from the photographer and/or clippings from the magazines where the photos were published. Often the notes are of a personal nature indicating circumstances of the photo shoot or feelings about the subject.
  - Subseries II.1 - Portraits - Unmounted
    - "A" general - Ascoli, Max Allen, woody (2) Alonso, Alicia - 1978 Anderson, Marion (2) Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh) (3) - 1967 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 72)
    - "B" general - Bacharach, Burt Bacon, Francis - 1968 Baez, Joan - 1968 Balanchine, George Barth, John Belgrave, Cynthia with husband and children - 1963 Bellow, Saul (2) with son Adam, NY - 1971 Benchley, Peter Ben-Gurion, David (2) - 1967, 1972 Berlin, Irving with wife, Ellen Mackay Bernstein, Leonard (2) Boroughs, William (2) Brando, Marlon Brown, Helen Gurley (2) - 1967 Buck, Pearl Buckley, William F. (2) - 1972, undated Burjaily, Vance (Offsite-box 6, Folder 73)
    - "C" general - Calder, Alexander (6) Capote, Truman (3) - 1969 Carney, Art Carter, Jimmy Carter, Rosalyn - 1976 Casals, Pablo Cheever, John (See also: Oversize Material) Chevalier, Maurice Coltrane, John (2) - 1965 Condon, Richard (3) - 1972 [Cooper, Alice - See: Dali, Salvador; Minnelli, Liza] (Offsite-box 6, Folder 74)
    - Cambridge, Godfrey (9), 1960's (Offsite-box 6, Folder 75)
    - "D" general - Dahlberg, Edward (2) - 1969; 1971 Dali, Salvador (2) - 1973 Darden, Norma Davis, Bette (2) Davis, Stuart (2) - 1967 DeVries, Peter (2) Dietrich, Marlene Doctorow, E. L. (Offsite-box 6, Folder 76)
    - De Kooning, Willem (3) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 77)
    - "E" general - Egan, Daniel (2) Ellington, Duke (5) - 1960's Ellison, Ralph (Offsite-box 6, Folder 78)
    - "F-G" general Friedan, Betty Frost, David Ginzburg, Ralph Gonzalez, Xavier - 1964 Graham, Billy - 1963 Graham, Martha - 1975 [Grant Cary - See: Hayes, Helen] Goodman, Benny - 1969 Gregory, Dick Grooms, Red Gross, Chaim (2) - 1967, 1960's (Offsite-box 6, Folder 79)
    - Guccione, Bob (9) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 79a)
    - "H" general - [Hammarskold, Dag - See: Stevenson, Adlai] Hardwick, Elizabeth Hayes, Helen (2) Hellman, Lillian (2) - 1982 (See also: Oversize Material) Heschel, Abraham Joshua - 1968 Hertzberg, Arthur Hirshorn, Joseph Hoffman, Abbie - 1967 Hoffman, Dustin - [1968] Hopkins, Budd Hughes, Langston Hurt, Mississippi John (2) - 1965 Hutton, Lauren (Offsite-box 6, Folder 80)
    - "J" general - Jackson, Jesse - 1981 Jennings, Peter - 1967 Jhabvala, Ruth - 1987 Johnson, Lyndon B. (3) Johnson, Philip Jong, Erica (Offsite-box 6, Folder 81)
    - Jones, James Earl (7), 1960's (Offsite-box 6, Folder 82)
    - "K" general - Kazin, Alfred - 1987 Kertész, André (2) Kissinger, Henry (2) Knaths, Karl Koch, Ed - 1980 Krasner, Lee Krementz, Jill Kunitz, Stanley - 1971 Kuralt, Charles - 1970 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 83)
    - Kennedy - Kennedy, Edward M. (Ted), (2) [Kennedy, Jacqueline - See: Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy] Kennedy, John Jr. (4) Kennedy, Robert F. (4) - 1964, 1967 [Kennedy, Rose - See: Wagner, Robert F.] Kennedy, William (2) - 1981 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 84)
    - "L" general - Laurence, William Leonard [Lerner, Jay - See: Bernstein, Leonard] Lerner, Max Levin, Mayer - 1960's Lilienthal, David E. Lindsay, Howard (2) Lindsay, John Lloyd Webber, Andrew Loren, Sophia - ca 1967 Ludlum, Robert (Offsite-box 6, Folder 85)
    - "M" general - McDonald, David, J. McGovern, George Matthiessen, Peter Maxwell, William (2) Mazzo, Kay (2) Meir, Golda - 1974 Merwin, W. S. Michener, James Miller, Arthur (2) - 1966 Minnelli, Liza - 1972 [Mondale, Joan - See: Carter, Rosalynn] Moore, Henry Moore, Marianne Morrison, Toni Moses, Robert Murdoch, Rupert (Offsite-box 7, Folder 86)
    - McLuhan, Marshall (5) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 87)
    - Mailer, Norman (4) (See also: Oversize Material) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 88)
      See Also:
      Oversize Material
    - Newman, Barnett (3) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 89)
    - Nureyev, Rudolf (5) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 90)
    - "O" general - O'Keefe, Georgia (2) - 1972 Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy (5) - 1966, 1872, undated (Offsite-box 7, Folder 91)
    - "P" general - Pavarotti, Luciano Paley, Grace - 1973 [Peabody, Jill - See: Uris, Leon] Perelman, S. J. Prince, Harold (Hal) Puzo, Mario (Offsite-box 7, Folder 92)
    - Partch, Harry (4) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 93)
    - "R" general - Reagan, Ronald - 1972 [Rice, Tim - See: Lloyd Webber, Andrew] Rivers, Larry (2) Robards, Jason (2) Rockefeller brothers includes Nelson, David Sr., Winthrop, John D. III., and Laurance Rothko, Mark Rubin, Jerry - 1967 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 94)
    - "Sa-Sm" general - Sacks, Oliver W. St. Denis, Ruth (2) - 1968 [Sawyer, Diane - See: Kuralt, Charles] Segal, George - 1974 Shanker, Albert (2) - 1968 [Shaw, Ted - See: St. Denis, Ruth] Sheed, Wilfred Shor, Toots - 1975 Singer, Isaac Bashevis (See also: Overize Material) Smith, R. [?] Smith, W. Eugene (2) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 95)
    - "Sn-Sz" general - Snowdon, Antony Armstrong-Jones, Earl of with Princess Margaret Solti, George (2) - 1968, 1969 (See also: Oversize Material) Sondheim, Stephen Springsteen, Bruce (2) Stafford, Jean Steig, Jerry - 1963 Steinem, Gloria - 1972, undated Stokowski, Leopold [Stone, Sly - See: Wonder, Stevie] Styron, William - 1965 (See also: Oversize Material) Sullivan, Ed (See also: Musical Groups - The Beatles) Swados, Harvey (2) [Swanson, Gloria - See: Hayes, Helen] (Offsite-box 7, Folder 96)
    - Simon, Sidney (4) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 97)
    - Simone, Nina (5), 1963-1964 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 98)
    - Stevenson, Adlai (5), circa 1960 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 99)
    - "T-U" general - [Tallchief, Maria - See: Nureyev, Rudolf] Tucker, Richard (2) Updike, John (2) Uris, Leon (2) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 100)
    - Twiggy (4), 1967 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 101)
    - "V" general - Van Peebles, Melvin (3) Vaughan, Sarah (2) - 1965 Vidal, Gore [Vigard, Kristen - See: Shipp, John Wesley] Vreeland, Diana (2) (Offsite-box 7, Folder 102)
    - "W-Z" general - Wagner, Robert F. (2) Walker, Alice Wallice, Irving (2) - 1964 Warhol, Andy (4) - 1975 Warwick, Dionne Wiesel, Elie (4) - 1965 Winchell, Walter - 1975 Wonder, Stevie [Wolfe, Tom - See: Oversize Material] Zeckendorf, William Zinsser, William (Offsite-box 7, Folder 103)
    - Musical Groups - The Animals The Beatles (2) Simon and Garfunkel (3) Peter, Paul and Mary (Offsite-box 7, Folder 104)
    - Unidentified (Offsite-box 7, Folder 105)
  - Subseries II.2 - Portraits - Unmounted, by Other Photographers
    - By Alex Gotfryd - Benchley, Peter Drury, Allen Eisenhower, John S. D. Maynard, Joyce Roszak, Theodore Sacks, Oliver W. Scotto, Renata (Offsite-box 7, Folder 106)
    - By Howard Gotfryd - Gotfryd, Bernard - 1985 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 107)
    - By Richard Reinhold - Gotfryd, Bernard - 1982 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 108)
  - Subseries II.3 - Portraits - Mounted
    - "B general - Buckley, William F. - 1965 Burroughs, William (Offsite-box 8, Folder 109)
    - "C-D" general - Calas, Maria - 1964 Calder, Alexander (2) [Casals, Pablo - See: Stern, Isaac] Castro, Fidel [Davis, Sammy, Jr. - See: Oversize Material] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 110)
    - Carter, Jimmy includes Amy, Billy and Rosalynn [See also: Oversize Material] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 111)
    - "F-M" general - Flanner, Janet [Ford, Henry - See: Oversize Material] Gordimer, Nadine Johnson, Lyndon B. (2) Johnson, Philip Kennedy, Robert F. Kunitz, Stanley Leary, Timothy McLuhan, Marshall [Mailer, Norman - See: Oversize Material] Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley) [Mindszenty, Jozsef (Cardinal) - See: Oversize Material] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 112)
    - "N-P" general - Nixon, Richard with family [Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy - See: Oversize Material] Podhoretz, Norman - undated (Offsite-box 8, Folder 113)
    - "R-So" general - [Ram Das (Alpert, Richard) - See: Leary, Timothy] Roth, Phillip - 1967 Sihanouk, Norodom, Prince (3) - 1979 Slavitt, David Smith, W. Eugene [Solti, George - See: Oversize Material] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 113a)
    - "St-W" general - Stern, Isaac Stevenson, Adlai (2) Stokowski, Leopold [Styron, William - See: Oversize Material] Susann, Jacqueline [Wolfe, Tom - See: Oversize Material] (Offsite-box 9, Folder 114)
  - Subseries II.4 - Subjects - Unmounted
    - Art - Howard Wise Gallery, Light Art, 1967 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 115)
    - Bridges - various (Offsite-box 9, Folder 116)
    - Buildings - various (Offsite-box 9, Folder 117)
    - Buildings - Churches (Offsite-box 9, Folder 118)
    - Buildings - Institutions - Halfway House [Village Haven?] (Offsite-box 9, Folder 119)
    - Buildings - Monuments (Offsite-box 9, Folder 119a)
    - Buildings - Museums (Offsite-box 9, Folder 120)
    - Buildings - Nightclubs (Offsite-box 9, Folder 121)
    - Buildings - Printing and Publishing - New York Daily Mirror, [1963] (Offsite-box 9, Folder 122)
    - Buildings - Prisons - Rikers Island (Offsite-box 9, Folder 123)
    - Buildings - Restaurants - Luchow's (Offsite-box 9, Folder 124)
    - Celebrations and Events - various (Offsite-box 9, Folder 125)
    - Celebrations and Events - Party at the "Scene" (Offsite-box 9, Folder 125a)
    - Children - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 126)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 127)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - Newark Riots (13) (Offsite-box 10, Folder 127a)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - Anti-Vietnam (Offsite-box 10, Folder 128)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - Pro-Vietnam (Offsite-box 10, Folder 129)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - Against the play The Deputy, [1964] (Offsite-box 10, Folder 130)
    - Demonstrations and Protests - Resurrection City, Washington, D.C., [1968] (Offsite-box 10, Folder 131)
    - Funerals and Memorials - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 132)
    - Border Station (Offsite-box 10, Folder 133)
    - Neighborhoods - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 134)
    - Occupations - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 135)
    - Occupations - Police (Offsite-box 10, Folder 136)
    - Parks - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 137)
    - Performing Arts - various, 1967, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 138)
    - Performing Arts - Powder Ridge Rock Festival, Middlefield CT, 1970 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 138a)
    - Poverty - various (5) (Offsite-box 10, Folder 138b)
    - Sports - various, 1970's, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 139)
    - Street Scenes - Atlantic City (Offsite-box 10, Folder 140)
    - Street Scenes - New York City, 1986, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 141)
    - Transportation - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 142)
    - Transportation - Subways (Offsite-box 10, Folder 143)
    - Various and Unidentified, 1968, undated (Offsite-box 10, Folder 144)
    - Various and Unidentified - Billboards/signage (3) (Offsite-box 10, Folder 145)
  - Subseries II.5 - Subjects - Mounted
    - Celebrations and Events - various, 1968, 1976 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 146)
    - Hospitals - various (Offsite-box 10, Folder 147)
- Series III. Oversize Material
  - Subseries III.1 - Portraits - Unmounted (Box Flat files, Folder OS-1)
    - Portraits - Unmounted Cheever, John - undated Hellman, Lillian - undated Singer, Isaac Bashevis - undated (Box Flat files, Folder OS-1)
  - Subseries III.2 - Portraits - Mounted
    General
    Some mounted prints have magazine clippings mounted on verso.
    - Portraits - Mounted - "A-Ma" Arafat, Yasir - undated Carter, Jimmy with Rosalynn and Amy Carter - undated Davis, Sammy, Jr. - undated Ford, Henry with daughter Anne - undated Mailer, Norman - undated (Box Flat files, Folder OS-2)
    - Portraits - Mounted - "Mi - W" Mindszenty, Jozsef (Cardinal) - undated Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy - undated Solti, George - undated Styron, William - undated Wolfe, Tom - undated (Box Flat files, Folder OS-3)
  - Subseries III.3 - Manuscript Material
    - Posters and Clippings (Box Flat files, Folder OS-4)
- Series IV. Manuscript Material
  Subseries IV.1 Correspondence contains letters, e-mails, postcards and telegrams from 1961-2009. Several letters of thanks came from Gotfryd's subjects, including ones from Ralph Ginzburg, Elia Kazan, David Lilienthal, Meyer Schapiro and Harvey Swados.
  Subseries IV.2 Ephemera includes auction catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements, invitations and tickets. A large number of press passes are for events; they include the 1976 Olympics, 1968 Nixon Presidential Campaign, 1965 and 1978 Westminster Kennel Club Dog Show and Pope John Paul I's 1976 visit to New York. The subseries contains eleven postcards, printed by Fotofolio, featuring Gotfryd's photographs. There is also a student's master's thesis, in Polish, about Gotfryd's photographic work. Oversize material, such as full newspaper sheets and exhibition posters, is housed in flat files and listed separately.
  - Subseries IV.1 - Correspondence
    - To Bernard Gotfryd - "A-F", 1963-2009 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 148)
    - To Bernard Gotfryd - "G-O", 1961-2008 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 149)
    - To Bernard Gotfryd - "P-S", 1963-2006 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 150)
    - To Bernard Gotfryd - "T-Z", 1968-2009 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 151)
    - To Bernard Gorfryd - Unidentified or first name only, 1966, 2004, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 152)
    - To Others, 1961-1970 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 153)
  - Subseries IV.2 - Ephemera
    - Miscellaneous Ephemera, 1976, 1996-2007 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 154)
    - Articles and Poetry written by Bernard Gotfryd (See also: Magazines), 1976, 2002, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 155)
    - Auction Catalog, 1978 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 156)
    - Biographic Information (Offsite-box 11, Folder 157)
    - Book Covers (Offsite-box 11, Folder 158)
    - Book Reviews and Advertising, 1991-2007, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 159)
    - Clippings, magazine, 1966-1999, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 160)
    - Clippings, newspaper -- with Gotfryd Photographs, 1964-1974, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 161)
    - Clippings, newspaper -- Exhibition Announcements and Reviews, 1969-1980, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 162)
    - Clippings, newspaper - Interviews, 1973, 1984, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 163)
    - Exhibit Announcements (Offsite-box 11, Folder 164)
    - Invitations, 1976-2009, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 165)
    - Magazine Covers - Newsweek, 1967-1982 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 166)
    - Magazines - Newsweek, 1968-1973, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 167)
    - Magazines - Infinity, 1968-1973, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 168)
    - Magazines - Proof Pages, 1967, 1982, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 169)
    - Newsletters, 1964-1987 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 170)
    - Plains, Georgia Coloring Book, 1976 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 171)
    - Postcards (Offsite-box 11, Folder 172)
    - Miedzy Dokumentem A Kreacja Tworczosc Bernarda Gotfryda(Master's Thesis about Bernard Gotfryd's photographic work, by Agnieska Sieradzka, in polish), 2009 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 173)
    - Press Passes - Misc. Events, 1965-1994, undated (Offsite-box 12, Folder 174-175)
    - Press Passes - Musical Events, 1965-1971, undated (Offsite-box 12, Folder 176)
    - Press Passes - Political Events (Offsite-box 12, Folder 177-178)
    - Press Passes - Religious Events, 1968, 1979, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 179)
    - Press Passes - Sporting Events, 1965-1978, undated (Offsite-box 13, Folder 180)
    - Press Pins (Offsite-box 13, Folder 181)
    - Tickets, 1968-1980 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 182)
- Series V. Holocaust Survivor Material
  Series V. Holocaust Survivor Material, dating between 1990 and 2011, contains materials relating to Bernard Gotfryd's speaking engagements and writings about the Holocaust.
  Subseries V.1 contains three books written by Gotfryd
  Subseries V.2 contains Correspondence. Much of this is thank you notes and artwork from middleschool and highschool students.
  Subseris V.3 includes miscellaneous items such as writing drafts, a book awards list, a copy of a book review, and a copy of some biographical information about Gotfryd.
  Subseries V.4 includes magazines which contain articles written by Gotfryd.
  Subseries V.5 contains two scrapbooks created by students at McAuley Highschool in response to Gotfryds talk on the Holocaust.
  - Subseries V.1- Books - written by Bernard Gotfryd, 1990, 2008, 2009
    - Book: Anton the dove fancier and other tales of the Holocaust, in English, 1990 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 183)
    - Book: Widuje ich w snach: Nowe opowiadania. (I can see them in my dreams: The New Stories), in Polish and English, 2008 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 184)
    - Book: Stolarz Izaak, Za Murem (Isaac Carpenter, and Behind the Wall), in Polish, 2009 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 185)
  - Subseries V.2 - Correspondence and Artwork
    - Correspondence - general, 1991-2011 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 186)
    - Thank you notes: from students - unidentified schools, 1997 - 2010 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 187)
    - Thank you notes: from students at ACORN High School for Social Justice, 2009 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 188)
    - Thank you notes: from students at Flushing International School, 2008 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 189)
    - Thank you notes: from students at Booker T. Washington Middle School, 2008, 2009 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 190-191)
    - Thank you artwork, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 192)
  - Subseries V.3 - Ephemera
    - Miscellaneous Ephemera - Student book report biographical information on Bernard Gotfryd copy of book review book award list (Offsite-box 15, Folder 193)
    - Writing Drafts: for book Anton the Dove Fancier (Offsite-box 15, Folder 194-195)
  - Subseries V.4 - Magazines
    - Magazines: Jewish Monthly, 1984-1985 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 196)
    - Magazines: Midstream, 1985-1991 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 197)
    - Magazines: Moment, 1988 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 198)
    - Magazines: Renewal, 1986 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 199)
  - Subseries V.5 - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook: from students at McAuley Highschool, 2008 (Offsite-box 16, Volume 1)
    - Scrapbook: from students at McAuley Highschool, 2010 (Offsite-box 16, Volume 2)